I keep seeing on the internet a lot of
people really concerned about the fact
that we're taking the drastic steps we
are and the impact it's having on the
economy when the numbers aren't even
close to the annual flu rate and so in
hopes that people's lack of math skills
doesn't kill us all I'm doing this video
to explain why kovat 19 is not the flu
and it is so much worse without giving
you a math lesson even though I will be
bringing numbers into it so with the flu
that when you have the flu the
percentage of people that you infect on
an average basis is 1.3 which means when
you're recovered you leave one person
behind plus about a 30% increase the are
for kovat 19 is 2 to 3 which means if
you're out in the world infecting people
you're doubling or tripling the amount
of people infected in a very short
period of time the death rate is much
higher the numbers right now for the flu
are higher on the annual basis but the
flu runs its course we know what that
does that's the annual rate we're only
how far into the year and we already
have 2 over 10,000 deaths from this
thing so they we know that the death
rate for the flu is roughly one in a
thousand the death rate for Kovan 19 is
30 out of a thousand this is 30 times
more deadly than the flu we cannot
afford for it to be as rampant as the
flu especially since the incubation
period for this thing is 5 to 14 days
some people are asymptomatic genes
they're out spreading it around without
knowing that's why we're in our houses
socially isolating so we can hopefully
curb this and flatten the curve the
exposure the incubation period for the
flu is 1 to 4 days and you know you have
it you're a key your although you might
be infectious for one day before you
start to show symptoms you're not
infectious for a week before you start
to show symptoms the math on this thing
makes it makes it scary it's kind of the
perfect disease just infection to spread
throughout the population
it's the perfect infectious disease
our politicians I'm the first to say
that they cannot handle complex issues
they cannot understand things and
extrapolate to the future but they're
the best we have right now and we need
to be listening to the advice they're
giving not without thinking about it but
understand that if you don't understand
the complex math the it's not even that
complex
you don't understand the math of
exponential growth and death rate
percentages then please leave it up to
the experts please leave it up to those
of us who've passed high school math and
university math to say this thing is
different there's a reason we're all
staying home our governments are not
taking our would not be shutting down
our economies to the extent they have if
this wasn't as serious it as it is we
don't have mass collusion on a global
level this would have to be the biggest
conspiracy theory every time it hits a
new country the politicians scramble
wait to do lockdown until way too late
and we can see that playing out again
and again and again we can figure out
the rest we right now it's about
flattening the curve and keeping as many
people alive as possible who would die
for this thing then we can figure out
how we feed ourselves how we get our
economy back if that's if that's what
you all want because that's not what I
want I don't want to go back to normal
I want to create a beautiful world of
abundance and joy and peace for everyone
like once we have a ceasefire from work
we please go back to not have any more
but right now please just listen to the
math please stay home this is not the
flu and it is much more serious thank
you